进来，我等很久了
Come in.I've been waiting for you.
我只是…天啊，莫妮卡
Hi,I just…Oh,my God! Monica!Oh,my God!
抱歉抱歉，我正在睡午觉
I'm sorry! I was I was taking a nap.
你从何时开始 用那种怪姿势睡觉？
Since when do you take naps in that position?
莫妮卡，你是在等男人吧？ 拜托你说是在等男人
Tell me you were waiting for a guy. Please tell me.
没错，我在等男人，公司同事
Yes,I was. A guy.From work.
我最近跟同事约会
I'm seeing a guy from work!
那个长得像雷·利奥塔（影星）亲切版的 帅哥服务生？
That cute waiter guy that looks like a nonthreatening Ray Liotta?
就是他
That one!
我马上就闪人 我只是回来拿件外套
Give me a second. I'm just going to grab a jacket.
等我回来可要告诉我详情
When I get back,I want every little detail.
他可能来了
Maybe that's him.
或许…
Okey ，maybe
只是乔伊跟罗斯
It's just Joey and Ross.
你们不是去看电影吗？
Why aren't you at the movie?
对啊，可是罗斯讲电话太吵 我们被电影院轰了出来
Ross was so loud,they threw us out.
电影太吵，我当然得大声讲
I had to talk loud because the movie was loud!
他打电话去伦敦
-He's talking to London.
为什么？他找到艾蜜莉了？
-Why？Did he get in touch with Emily?
还没，但是他打给女方亲戚 希望有人愿意帮他
No,not yet. He's hoping that someone will help him get in touch with her.
就算我说错名字又如何 你这大惊小怪的笨蛋
I don't care if I said some other girl's name,you prissy old twit!
罗斯，你巴结亲家真有一套
Way to suck up to the family!
真高兴大家都在 我们公司终于买免皱传真纸了
I'm so glad you're all here. My office finally got wrinkle-free fax paper!
本集播出：“菲比讨厌公共电视台”
The One Where Phoebe Hates PBS
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库桌
麦特勒布蘭
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
请问是霍普金奶妈吗？ 我找艾蜜莉
Hi,is this Nanny Hopkins? I'm looking for Emily.
沃森
Waltham.
抱歉，这是011447 4293474267吗？
Oh,I'm sorry. Is this 0-1-1-4-4-7-4-2-9-3-4-7-4-2-6-7?
是43不是42啊 哪个42？
Oh,it's "4-3," not 4-2.Well,which 4-2?
别过来，那是呕吐西装
No,no! Vomit tux!
放心，我送去干洗过了
Don't worry,I had it dry-cleaned.
呕吐西装？谁会吐在西装上？
Vomit tux?Who vomited on?
乔伊，你为何穿成这样？
You know what? What you up to,Joe?
我要上马拉松式电视节目
They're doing this telethon thing on TV.
我的经纪帮我争取当主持群
And my agent got me a job as cohost!
太棒了
That's great!
帮公共电视台做好事 又能增加曝光率
A little good deed for PBS,plus some TV exposure.
我乔伊最爱做这种事了
That's the kind of math Joey likes to do.
公视啊
Oh,PBS!
公视哪里不对了？
-What's wrong with PBS?
他们哪里对？
-What's right with them?
菲比，你为何不喜欢公视？
Why don't you like PBS?
因为我妈自杀之后 我个人非常难过
Right after my Mom killed herself,I was in a bad place,personally.
所以我想写信给芝麻街 心情应该会好一点
I thought I'd write to Sesame Street.
因为我小时候 总觉得他们很亲切
Because they were nice when I was a little kid.
结果根本没人回信
No one ever wrote back.
那些布偶根本没有手指
A lot of those muppets don't have thumbs.
我只收到一个烂钥匙环 拜托，我那时住在纸箱里耶
All I got was a lousy key chain,and by that time,I was living in a box.
连钥匙都没有
I didn't have keys!
我很遗憾，菲比 我只是想做好事
I'm sorry,Phoebe.I wanted to do a good deed
就像你帮忙生小孩
like you did with the babies.
你才不是做善事 只是想上电视，根本就很自私
This isn't a good deed. You just want to get on TV. This is selfish.
你帮弟弟生小孩又怎么说？ 自私的不是只有我
What about you having those babies for your brother?That's selfish!
你胡说什么？
What are you talking about?
你的确是帮忙他们 不过自己心情也很好吧？
It was a nice thing,but it made you feel good,right?
那又如何？
Yeah,so?
因为你做善事心情好 也算是自私的一种
It made you feel good so that makes it selfish.
世界上根本就没有无私的好事
Look,there's no unselfish good deeds. Sorry.
明明就有 有很多行善的人都没有私心
Yes,there are totally good deeds that are selfless!
请你举出一个例子
May I ask for one example?
就是有，例如…反正你不是
Yeah,it's You know,there's…No,you may not!
因为所有人都很自私
Because all people are selfish.
你说我自私？
Are you calling me selfish?
你难道不是人？
Are you calling you people?
菲比，很抱歉戳破你的美梦
Sorry to burst that bubble,Phoebe,
世界上没有无私的善事
but selfless good deeds don't exist.
你也知道圣诞老人吧？
You know the deal on Santa Claus?
我一定会找到一件无私的善事 打败你这个邪恶天才
I'll find a selfless good deed. I'm going to beat you,you evil genius!
喂
Hello
罗斯吗？
Hello Ross？
艾蜜莉，天啊，是艾蜜莉 大家不要吵！
Oh,my God! It's Emily!It's Emily,everyone!
嗨
Hi
我打来只是要告诉你 别再骚扰我家人了，再见
I'm only ringing to say stop harassing my relatives. Goodbye.
等一下，就算你挂断 我也会继续
You can hang up,but I'll keep calling everyone in England...
如果要打给所有英国人 才能逼你跟我说话
...if that's what it takes to get you to talk to me.
真的？你想谈什么？
Really? About what?
你是我太太，我们已经结婚
Look,you're my wife. We're married.
而且我爱你，我很想你
You know,I love you.I really miss you.
我也很想你
I miss you too.
至少我认为如此
At least,I think I do.
她肯跟我说话了
She's talking.
乔伊，你刚刚 为何提到圣诞老人？
When you said "the deal with Santa," you meant...?
根本没有这号人物
That he doesn't exist.
这样啊
Right.
钱德，你听说 莫妮卡的地下情人了吗？
Chandler,have you heard about Monica's secret boyfriend?
知道，她…她是提过
Yeah,she might have mentioned him.
我们到底何时 才能认识这个服务生？
So,Mon,when are we going to meet this new,secret waiter man?
他很害羞，现在还没准备 认识大家
I don't think he's up to meeting everyone yet.
我想他还没准备好
Yeah,I don't think he's up to it.
我不管，我想见他 她说对方床上一级棒
I want to meet this guy who's the best sex she ever had.
真的？
Really?
她说过？你说过？
That's what you heard? You said that?
大概吧
I might have.
这有什么好笑？
Why is that funny?
因为我很为他高兴
Because I'm very happy for him.
你真是走狗运！
And you! You lucky dog!
嗨 嘿
Hi！-Hey
艾蜜莉愿意跟我复合
Well，Emily's willing to work on the relationship.
太好了 她要我去伦敦
That's great!In London.
什么？
What？
她要我搬到伦敦去
She wants me to move to London.
可是你住在这里
But you live here.
我这是废话
You know that.
你打算怎么办？
-What will you do?
不知道，我不能丢下班
-I don't know.I mean,I can't leave Ben.
你可以跟他用视讯会议
-You can just video-conference with him.
我还不够格当爸爸
I'm not ready to have a child.
只要跟卡萝、苏珊谈谈 一定能说服她们带班搬到伦敦
I bet if I talked to Carol and Susan...I could convince them to move to London with Ben.
想必你前妻一定乐意搬到国外 帮你挽回新太太
I'm sure your ex-wife would be more than happy to move...so you can patch things up with your new wife.
不是不可能啊
It could happen.
罗斯，我们才不搬到伦敦 我们的生活重心都在这里
Ross,we are not moving to London. We already have lives here.
但是那边很棒
But it'd be great.
有一流的戏院、口音、茶
They have great theater...great accents.Tea.
英国还有女王
They have a queen.
所以呢？
-So?
她是女人
-She's a woman.
爸爸
-Daddy! -Hey!
告诉你，我们要搬到伦敦了
Guess what? We're moving to London!
谁要搬去伦敦？
-Who's going to London?
不是我们
-Nobody's going to London.
欢迎莅临伦敦，总督
Welcome to London,governor.
太棒了，到时伦敦就有大笨钟 跟我们小班了
Right,right. It'll be great because we'll have Big Ben and little Ben in the same city.
赶快去整理行李
Go pack!
你们看，他想去
See? See,he wants to go.
是啊，我们都让三岁小鬼 决定家里大事
Yeah,we leave all our big decisions to the 3-year-old.
这就像“三人行”嘛
Come on,come on. It'll be just like Three's Company...
只是另外两个 换成一个小孩跟我老婆
...only there's a kid and my wife...
你们就是里面的同性恋角色
...and you're the gay ones.
你好，欢迎，幸会
How you doing? Welcome. Good to see you.
这就是你的电话
This'll be your phone.
真好 不过应该没有人会打来找我
That's great.But I'm not really expecting a lot of calls.
你负责接电话接受捐款
No,you answer it and take pledges.
我是主持人
But I'm the host.
盖瑞卡林才是主持人 你负责接电话
Gary Collins is the host. You'll be answering the phone.
你恐怕搞不清楚状况 我是雷莫瑞医生
You don't seem to understand. I was Dr. Drake Ramoray.
你负责这支电话，医生
Well,here's your phone,doctor.
我竟然找不到一件无私的善行
I can't believe I can't find a selfless good deed.
以前我家隔壁有个老头
You know that old guy that lives next to me?
我偷溜到他家
I snuck over there
帮他打扫前廊的落叶
and raked up the leaves on his front stoop.
他捉到我之后 强迫我喝苹果汁、吃饼干
But he caught me,and he force-fed me cider and cookies.
可是我却很开心，那个老混蛋
Then I felt wonderful. That old jackass!
或许乔伊说得对 所有好事的出发点都有私心
Maybe Joey's right. Maybe all good deeds are selfish.
我一定要找到一件无私的善行
I will find a selfless good deed.
毕竟我才刚生出三个宝宝
I gave birth to three children...
不能让他们在 乔伊有理的世界里长大
...and I won't let them be raised in a world where Joey's right!
莫妮卡
Monica
可以问你有关烹饪的问题吗？
Can I ask you a cooking question?
当然
Sure
如果你用炉子烹饪
If you're cooking on the stove...
是否代表你新男友在床上 比理查还厉害？
...that means your new boyfriend is better in bed than Richard?
钱德
Chandler
有吗？
Is he?
我要尊重秘密新男友的隐私
I think I'll respect the privacy of my new,secret boyfriend.
为什么？
Why?
如果我是他，又知道 自己是你碰过最棒的情人
If this guy was me...and it's me who'd learned that it was me who was the best you'd ever had...
我一定乐歪了
...I'd be like this:
艾蜜莉，虽然我很爱你 但是我不能丢下班去伦敦
All right,Emily.As much as I love you I'm sorry,I can't move to London without Ben.
我知道这很为难你
I understand that would be difficult.
请你考虑搬过来好吗？
Would you consider moving here?
你本来就打算搬来 为何不现在就来呢？
You were moving here anyway.Why can't you just do that?
我不知道，只是…
I don't know. It's just
我知道自己到目前为止 都蠢头蠢脑
But I know that even though I've been a complete idiot up till now...
但是你还是应该过来 我们才能继续走下去
...you have to come here.You have to,so we can work this out together.
好吧
All right.
你刚说好？
Did you just say "all right"?
没错，现在换我是白痴
I did. Now I'm the idiot.
艾蜜莉，太棒了 我们就像坠入爱河的白痴
Emily,that is so great!It'll be great!We're going to be like two idiots in love!
罗斯，有件事还是让我很担心
There's one thing that really scares me still.
你尽管说
-Yes,tell me.
你要知道当天婚礼 我在亲朋好友面前有多丢脸
-You must understand...how humiliating it was for me at the altar in front of my family and friends.
我知道，我非常抱歉
I know. I am so sorry.
当我决定原谅你 却看到你跟她赶着上飞机
And then,after deciding to forgive you seeing you at the airport,catching our plane with her.
同样，我的错
Again,very sorry.
我根本无法与她共处一室
I mean,I can't be in the same room as her.
我光想到你跟她共处一室 就快气坏了
It drives me mad thinking of you being in the same room as her.
艾蜜莉，我跟瑞秋根本没什么 我爱的是你
Emily,there is nothing between Rachel and me.I love you.
好吧
All right.
我去纽约，我们再试试看
I'll come to New York,and we'll try to make this work.
太好了
That's so great!
只要你答应不再见瑞秋
As long as you don't see Rachel anymore.
我就问艾蜜莉愿不愿意来纽约 她答应了
I asked Emily if she would come to New York.And she said yes.
太好了
Great!
不不不
No No No
条件是我不准再见瑞秋
Only if I promise never to see Rachel again.
为什么？ 什么？不行
What? You can't
你怎么说？
What did you say?
我说要考虑 我到底该怎么决定？
I'd think about it. How am l supposed to make this decision?
我这是在问你们
I'm actually asking you!
你不能就此不见瑞秋 她是你的好朋友
Well，you can't just not see Rachel anymore.She is one of your best friends.
但是他也不能不见艾蜜莉 她可是他老婆
Yeah!But,he can't not exactly see Emily.I mean that's his wife!
对 也是
That's true!
你跟瑞秋从中学就认识 不能说不见就不见
Yeah, but you've known Rachel since High School and you cannot just cut her out of your life.
你说得也对
That's true!
谢谢你们的帮忙 问题解决了
Thanks for the help. Problem solved!
喂 莫妮卡
Hello！-Hi，Monica
乔伊，我们看了一整天电视 你到底何时才会出现？
Oh hey Joey! We've been watching all day, When will you be on TV?
我经纪人搞错了 反正我上了电视就有曝光率
There was kind of a mix-up in my agent's office...but I'm still on TV,and that's good exposure.
你没上电视啊
You're not on TV.
好吧，现在呢？
How about now?
有了，看到他了
There he is!
嗨，纽约
Hello,New York!
问题是这里有整支鸭 不过管他的
Maybe just put the whole duck in there. Who cares?
我先处理鸭腿
Now I got the legs.
我说过多少次 不准看烹饪频道
How many times have I told you to never watch the cooking channel?
嗨，钱德 嘿
Hi，Chandler.-Hi.
我来要回乔伊上次借的烤盘
-I need that broiling pan that Joey borrowed.
那是你的？
That was yours?
我们上次用来 盛小鸭吐出来的虫子
We used it when the duck was throwing up caterpillars.
在“威廉索诺玛”秋季刊27页买的
Williams-Sonoma,fall catalog,page 27.
4到6周后送货到你家
Expect it in 4 to 6 weeks.
乔伊今天一整天都不在
Joey's at the telethon for the rest of the day.
整个家里就只有我们两个
We have the place to ourselves.
那又如何？
Yeah,so?
或许你想跟最佳情人 预约时间约会
Maybe you'd want to book some time with "the best you've ever had."
你知道吗，冠军，我自愿放弃
You know what,champ?I think I'll pass.
为什么？
Why?
Why？
什么意思？
What's your point?
瞧你一副得意洋洋的蠢相 换作是你，还会有性趣吗？
With all the stupid gloating,would you want to sleep with you?
或许有点困难，不过我会努力
Well,I think I'd be a little out of my league,but I'd give it a shot.
公视电视募捐
PBS Telethon.
乔伊，告诉你 我找到无私的善行了
I just wanted to let you know that I found a selfless good deed.
我刚去公园让蜜蜂叮我
I went down to the park and I let a bee sting me.
什么？这对谁有好处？
What good is that going to do?
这支蜜蜂在同伴面前 脸上有光
It helps the bee look tough in front of his bee friends.
蜜蜂很开心，我却很痛
The bee is happy,and I am definitely not.
蜜蜂叮了你就死了
You know,the bee probably died after he stung you.
可恶
Damn it!
各位，30秒后开始录影
Back on in 30 seconds,people!
抱歉，可以跟你换位子吗？
Excuse me,would you mind switching with me?
甭想，我刚好在镜头里
No way. I'm in the shot,man.
拜托，你已经在这里一天了
-You've been here all day!
我在接受捐款，别吵我！
-I'm taking pledges.
倒数计时3、2、1
And we're on three,two....
欢迎收看电视募捐
Welcome back to our fall telethon.
如果各位喜欢“太阳马戏团”
If you've been enjoying Cirque du Soleil...
以后还想收看同类型节目 方法很简单
...and you'd like to see more,it's very simple.
只要打电话捐款 并告诉我们的义工
All you have to do is call in a pledge...and tell one of our volunteers
你喜欢收看哪类型节目
what type of programming you
问你一个烤盘的问题好吗？
-Quick broiling pan question
价钱就是这么贵
-Yes,it really does cost that much.
或许你们下次可以考虑 用廉价盘子处理鸭子的呕吐物
Maybe next time your duck can puke in something from Pottery Barn.
够了
That's it.
我无法做决定
I cannot make this decision.
这实在太难了
It is too difficult.
我决定交给命运之神
I leave it entirely up to the gods of fate.
神奇8号球？
A Magic 8 Ball?
你开玩笑吧？ 怎么可以用玩具决定命运？
You can't be serious,You can't make this decision with a toy!
这可不是玩具
It's not a toy.
我别无选择
I don't know what else to do!
不是追回老婆，失去好朋友
I either keep my wife and lose one of my best friends...
就是留下朋友 在30岁前离婚两次
...or I get divorced for the second time before I'm 30.
要是有人有更好的建议 现在就说出来
If anyone else has a better suggestion,let's hear it.
否则我真的没有办法
Because I got nothing!
大家别害羞，各种建议都可以
Don't be shy.Any suggestion will do.
好吧
Okay,then.
开始了
Here we go.
神奇8号球 我是不是不该再见瑞秋？
Magic 8 Ball...should I never see Rachel again?
待会再问
"Ask Again Later."
这个答案不够好
Later is not good enough!
待会再问
"Ask Again Later."
搞什么啊，这东西坏掉了
What the hell?This is broken! It is broken!
我来看看
Let me see.
钱德今晚会跟女人上床吗？
Will Chandler have sex tonight?
别指望了
"Don't Count On lt."
我倒觉得没坏掉
Seems like it works to me.
好，再来一次
Okay,one more time.
我是否不该再见瑞秋了？
Should I never see Rachel again?
神奇8号球！你问什么？
Magic 8 Ball! What did you ask?
今晚要看的电影 可以交由瑞秋决定吗？
Does...Rachel get to pick the movie that we're all going to see tonight?
很好，答案是什么？
Excellent. What's the answer?
看来斯泰拉今晚能找回她的快乐了（《当老牛碰上嫩草》）
Looks like Stella's gonna get her groove back tonight!
怎么了？听说那部片不错啊
What? I heard it was good.
公视电视募款
PBS Telethon.
嗨，乔伊
Hi,Joey.
嗨，菲比
Hey,Phoebe.
我要捐钱
I'd like to make a pledge.
我想捐200元
I would like to donate $200.
200元？你确定？
Two hundred dollars?
“芝麻街”可是伤你不浅
You sure? After what Sesame Street did to you?
我还是很生气
I'm still mad at them,
不过我也知道 很多妈妈没自杀的小孩很爱看
but they bring happiness to lots of kids whose moms didn't kill themselves.
为了支持这节目 我决定做件好事
By supporting them,I'm doing a good thing,
不过我自己可不开心
but I'm not happy about it.
你看，这就是无私的善行
So there! A selfless good deed.
难道你捐钱没有一点开心？
You don't feel good about donating the money?
难过死了 我本想用那笔钱买支黄金鼠
No,it sucks! I was saving up to buy a hamster.
黄金鼠？那种宠物 10元就买得到
A hamster? Those things are,like,$10.
我喜欢的那支可没那么便宜
Not the one I had my eye on.
看来今年的募款 已经超过去年总额，谢谢各位
It looks like we have surpassed last year's pledge total.Thank you!
打破纪录的捐款是由 我们的义工募得
And the pledge that did it was taken by one of our volunteers.
而且这位还穿得很体面
Oh,boy! And may I say,one of our sharpest dressed volunteers.
这位就是乔伊崔比亚尼
Mr. Joseph Tribbiani!
乔伊上电视了
Oh,look!Joey's on TV!
太棒了
Isn't that great?
我的捐款让乔伊上了电视
My pledge got Joey on TV!
这真是让我…糟糕
That makes me feel so…Oh,no!
或许我先前太得意了
Look...Maybe I got carried away before,
不过有件事要告诉你
but there's something you got to know.
如果我表现得很好也是因为你
If I'm the best,it's only because you made me the best.
说下去
Keep talking.
跟你在一起之前 我根本表现平平
I was nothing before you.
你可以打去问我以前那些女友
Call the other girls and ask.
你一定很快就问完了
Which wouldn't take long.
但是我跟你…我们在一起…
But when I'm with you,and we're together...
我…的…天…啊
...oh,my God!
真的？
-Really?
天…啊
-Oh,my God!
如果你不想再跟我上床 我也能体谅
I understand if you never want to sleep with me again.
不过这决定就不对了
But that would be wrong.
我们太厉害了 不上床实在太可惜
We're too good.We owe it to sex!
如果真是这样…
If we owe it!
天啊
Oh,my!
乔伊何时回来？
When will Joey be home?
我们应该不需要等他
I was kind of hoping we could do this without him.
没关系，手套不用脱
No,no,no! Leave the gloves on.
可是我刚在清厕所
I cleaned the bathroom.
那就脱掉吧 好
Why don't we lose the gloves.
让大家看看谁才是高手 好
All right. Let's show them how it's done.Okey
这不包括在内
-You know that wasn't part of it?
我知道
-I know.
嗨，你准备好没？ 我们要迟到了
You ready? We're going to be late.
迟到什么？
-For what?
看电影啊？你没忘吧？
-For Stella,remember?
还有20分钟斯泰拉就能找回快乐了
She's getting her groove back in 20 minutes.
我完全忘记了
I totally forgot about that.
你不介意我爽约一次吧？ 我正在等艾蜜莉的电话
Can I take a rain check? I'm waiting for a call from Emily.
没关系
Sure,I guess.
听说你不用去伦敦了，好耶
I hear you don't have to go to London.
事情没那么简单 我们还有很多问题
It's not that easy. There's still a lot of relationship stuff.
例如？
Like what?
就是一些问题
Just stuff.
艾蜜莉对我有些要求
You know,kind of what Emily wants.
你可以告诉我 或许我帮得上忙
Talk to me. Maybe I can help.
不行，你帮不上忙
No，No，You can't help.
这件事你帮不上忙
I have to do this without your help.
我知道你自己办得到
I know you can do that too.
但是如果你想找人谈谈…
I'm just saying if you need to talk....
谢了
Thanks.
罗斯
Ross
无论艾蜜莉有何要求 你答应就是了
Whatever it is that Emily wants...just give it to her.
最重要的是你爱她
The bottom line is that you love her.
她怎么要求，你就怎么做
Fix whatever she wants fixed.
答应就对了
Just do it.
你总得试试看
You're going to have to try.
不试试以后一定会后悔
You'll hate yourself if you don't.
快接电话啊，我都快被逼疯了
Come on,answer it!
喂，亲爱的
Hi,sweetie.
我很好
Good.
我考虑过你的要求
Yes,I've been thinking...about that thing you wanted me to do.
我办得到
I can do it.
你愿意来纽约吗？
Will you come to New York?
以前没试过这招 我也没
-Never done that before. -Nope.